<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevOps on Kelvas blog</title><link>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/categories/devops/</link><description>Recent content in DevOps on Kelvas blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © Kévin Sibué 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/categories/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publish automatically Hugo blog with GitHub Actions</title><link>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/auto-publish-with-actions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/auto-publish-with-actions/</guid><description>Repetitive actions are dangerous. Especially if they are simple. We tend to pay less and less attention to them and in the end, we make mistakes. Fortunately it is possible, not to say recommended, to automate these actions.
So today, as you may have guessed, we&amp;rsquo;re going to change the theme a bit and talk about the pipeline on GitHub Actions.
The context #I love to write and share, therefore I have this technical blog allowing me to pass on what I learn and what I think is useful to others.</description></item><item><title>Firebase and Azure DevOps</title><link>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/firebase-azure-devops/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/firebase-azure-devops/</guid><description>Firebase #As I have already mentioned in this article, Firebase is a service offered by Google for mobile and web developers to facilitate a large number of parts of application development:
Authentication NoSql Database cloud function Storage (image, video, &amp;hellip;) Web application hosting Real-time database Test lab Crash reporting in real time Remote config Cloud messaging It is therefore a very useful service for the rapid prototyping of an application and even for an application in production and all this for a very modest price.</description></item></channel></rss>