<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>NET on Kelvas blog</title><link>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/categories/net/</link><description>Recent content in NET on Kelvas blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © Kévin Sibué 2024</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/categories/net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create a NuGet package</title><link>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/create_nuget_lib/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/create_nuget_lib/</guid><description>Whether you are working alone or in a company, duplicating code is never a good practice. It is one of the first rules in computer science: when you create something, you reuse it, consolidate it, but avoid recreating it, except in rare cases.
Our goal here is to create reusable libraries that can be easily integrated into any project or other library.
We will not address the issue of code obfuscation here.</description></item><item><title>Segmentation fault and .NET on Linux</title><link>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/segmentation-fault-dotnet-linux/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/segmentation-fault-dotnet-linux/</guid><description>Segmentation fault and .NET on Linux #For some time I have re-enabled one of my PC with a good Linux Manjaro, it&amp;rsquo;s very convenient to run tens of services continuously without having to leave my Mac on or at home.
And I wanted to experience .NET development with VSCode (to do Blazor I admit it) all on my Linux.
Of course I follow the Microsoft tutorials to set up the environment and I start here: https://docs.</description></item><item><title>Incomprehensible errors</title><link>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/incomprehensible-errors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kelvas09.github.io/blog/posts/incomprehensible-errors/</guid><description>As you&amp;rsquo;ve probably gathered from the previous articles, I mostly do iOS and Android mobile. But from time to time, I go outside this mobile bubble to do other things.
The interesting thing about doing Xamarin for mobile is that it&amp;rsquo;s easy to port our application to desktop environments. But when I left my iOS and Android cocoon, I quickly realized that the tools for desktop development were not necessarily as advanced as their smartphone brother.</description></item></channel></rss>